his love...or his life...
The Beguiled is a thriller, drama, war film directed by Don Siegel.
Offbeat Civil War drama in which a wounded Yankee soldier, after finding refuge in an isolated girls' school in
the South towards the end of the war, becomes the object of the young women's sexual fantasies.
The soldier manipulates the situation for his own gratification, but when he refuses to
completely comply with the girls' wishes, they make it very difficult for him to leave.
John McBurney, played by Clint Eastwood.
Martha, played by Geraldine Page.
Edwina, played by Elizabeth Hartman.
Carol, played by Jo Ann Harris.
Doris, played by Darleen Carr.
Hallie, played by Mae Mercer.
The Beguiled is a 1971 American Southern Gothic psychological thriller film directed by
Donald Siegel, starring Clint Eastwood, Geraldine Page and Elizabeth Hartman.
The script was written by Albert Maltz and is based on
the 1966 novel written by Thomas P.
Cullinan, originally titled A Painted Devil.
The film marks the third of five collaborations between Siegel and Eastwood, following Coogan's Bluff (1968) and Two
Mules for Sister Sara (1970), and continuing with Dirty Harry (1971) and Escape from Alcatraz (1979).
The film is set during the Civil War and follows a young resident named
Amy who finds an injured enemy soldier in the forest.
Amy and others in her community must decide whether or
not to treat him as the war continues.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, mississippi
river, slavery, sexual repression, sexual awakening.
The tone is emotional and intense.